Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Welcome to today's lecture.
欢迎来到今天的讲座。
And today we are going to wrap up the discussion about the performance,
今天我们将结束关于性能的讨论。
and then we are going to spend the main bulk of the lecture on file systems.
然后我们将在讲座的主要部分讨论文件系统。
Let me start.
让我开始吧。
So just to recap from last week,
上周的内容简要回顾一下，
last week, we talk a little bit about performance.
上周，我们稍微讨论了一下性能问题。
This is one way to model the performance, in particular,
这是一种建模性能的方法，特别是
for something like a network.
对于像网络这样的东西。
We are talking then that, for instance,
我们在讨论的是，例如，
if you send a packet with a certain number of b beats, say,
如果您发送一个带有特定数量的b节拍的数据包，比如说，
small b the network capacity,
小b网络容量
it's b capital b beats per second.
它是大写字母B，表示每秒节拍数。
Then this is a formula for latency a you have a factor s which
那么这是一个关于延迟的公式，其中有一个因子s。
is overhead to send that packet,
发送该数据包会产生开销。
for instance, of the system call.
例如，系统调用的例子。
And then plus a variable part,
然后再加上一个可变部分，
which is b is a number of it in the packet over the capacity of the link,
b是指在数据包中超过链路容量的数量。
capital b this formula also works reasonably well for transferring data
这个公式对于数据传输也相当有效。
from the disk.
从磁盘中。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
a thick the s it's represent the rotational latency,
厚度表示的是旋转延迟。
plastic time.
塑料时间。
This is one, and this is a formula for the latency.
这是一个，这是一个用于计算延迟的公式。
And you see, here is shown on this plot with a blue line.
你看，这个图上用蓝线表示出来了。
The intercept of the blue line with the y axis represents the s in this case,
蓝线与y轴的截距代表了这种情况下的s。
it's1,000 micro seconds.
这是1,000微秒。
And then here,
然后在这里，
the slope represent the bandwidth of the particular link.
斜率代表特定链路的带宽。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
we are going to have a link of 100 garbage per second.
我们每秒将有100个垃圾链接。
S was 1,000 micro seconds or 1 million seconds.
S是1,000微秒或1百万秒。
Then b is here on the y axis.
然后b在y轴上。
B it's 5,000 beats.
B 是 5,000 拍。
Then then you are going to get the corresponding 5,000 of our
那么你将会得到我们对应的5,000份。
I think that should be bytes is 5,000.
我认为应该是字节为5,000。
It's 5,000,
是5,000。
55100,000÷12 hundred one,
55100,000÷12百一等于45,916.67
2121hundred twenty five megabytes per second.
2121兆字节每秒。
That will give you 4,000 micro seconds or 4 millisecond.
这将给你 4,000 微秒或 4 毫秒。
If you are to s which is 1 millisecond,
如果你要设置s为1毫秒，
you are going to get 5 millisecond or 5,000 microsecond ok and then the other
你将获得5毫秒或5,000微秒，好的，然后还有其他的。
important matrix here is the effective bandwidth,
重要的矩阵在这里是有效带宽。
which is basically,
基本上，
if i'm sending a packet of this length,
如果我发送一个这样长度的数据包，
what is the effective boundaries for that?
这个的有效边界是什么？
Sending that packet?
正在发送该数据包吗？
And that obviously is a packet size.
这显然是一个数据包的大小。
In this case, b over the time,
在这种情况下，b随时间变化。
it takes to send a packet,
发送一个数据包所需的时间
which it does includes as the fix overhead.
其中包括了修复的开销。
And this is a formula,
这是一个公式，
b b capital b times s over b small b plus one.
b b 大写 B 乘以 s 除以小写 b 加一。
You notice that if s is zero,
你注意到如果 s 是零，
then the effective bandwidth is equal with capital b which is expected,
那么有效带宽就等于大写的B，这是预期的。
right?
对的吗？
Because there is no fixed overhead.
因为没有固定的开销。
Then the effective bandwidth,
然后是有效带宽，
you can send data as fast as the capacitor of the link.
你可以以链路的电容速度发送数据。
One important metric here is about its 1/2 power bandwidth.
这里的一个重要指标是其1/2功率带宽。
And half power boundary is a way to think about it.
半功率边界是一种思考的方式。
Is basically what is the size of the packet?
基本上，数据包的大小是多少？
In this case,
在这种情况下，
I need to send such that the effective boundary is to be half
我需要发送这样的东西，使得有效边界减半。
of the capacity of the league.
联盟的能力范围。
The overhead is not that very high overhead.
开销并不是非常高。
It just cuts my effective.
这只是削减了我的效果。
My capacity to have.
我的容量。
Right here is red.
这里是红色的。
You can see this curve with red is the effective bandwidth,
你可以看到这条红色曲线代表的是有效带宽。
again, versus the capacity of the link when the number of bits,
再次，当比特数增加时，与链路容量相比。
when the number of vc zero,
当 VC 的数量为零时，
obviously, here you have effective bandwidth.
显然，这里你有有效带宽。
It's zero.
是零。
On this plot, here on the right,
在这个图上，右边的部分，
this is a plot which has two y axis.
这是一个具有两个Y轴的图表。
On the left hand side is the latency, is a blue one.
左侧是延迟，用蓝色表示。
The blue curve of the blue line,
蓝线的蓝色曲线。
and the right hand side,
右侧部分，
you are going to have the bandwidth effective bandwidth, which is a red.
你将拥有带宽有效带宽，这是一个红色的。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Next, remember that we also did a little bit of queuing theory,
接下来，记住我们还学习了一点排队论。
mostly providing you some formula,
主要为您提供一些公式，
just summarize them here.
请在这里简要总结它们。
This is topic it's covered.
这是所涵盖的主题。
This is part of the exam,
这是考试的一部分。
the midterm topics sub you may get the problem,
期中考试的主题可能会涉及以下问题：
which is about doing theory or about performers.
这个问题是关于理论还是关于表演者的。
I have performance.
我有性能问题。
Anyway,
无论如何，
here,
这里，
you remember that this is a a queuing model.
你记得这是一个排队模型。
Obviously,
显然，
it's called the queuing model for a reason.
它被称为排队模型是有原因的。
It has a queue.
它有一个队列。
You have a bunch of requests here with the arrival rate,
这里有一堆请求，附带到达速率，
lambda a lambda is a number of requests,
lambda是一种请求的数量。
average number of requests per second arriving to the cure.
每秒到达治疗中心的平均请求数量。
The requests are removed from the queue as fast as they can be processed
请求会尽快从队列中移除，只要它们能够被处理。
by a server.
由服务器完成。
And the server process each request as a service rate,
服务器按照服务速率处理每个请求。
mu mu is over and over the service time.
牛牛一次又一次超过了服务时间。
How long it takes to service a particular request?
处理一个特定请求需要多长时间？
The way to think about if the server takes 100 million seconds to server request,
如果服务器花费1亿秒来处理请求的方式思考，
then obviously, mu,
那么显然，mu，
it's 1 second over 100 million seconds is then,
1秒是1亿秒的1/100000000
because you're gonna set of ten requests per second.
因为你将每秒发送十个请求。
So then another important parameter is square coefficient of variance
另一个重要的参数是方差的平方系数。
to characterize the systems.
对系统进行特征化。
The several utilization,
多种利用方式
the several realization is basically the average arrival rate
几种实现方式基本上是平均到达率。
over the average service rate.
超过平均服务速率。
And fundamentally,
从根本上说，
you do want these parameters to be less than one,
你希望这些参数小于一。
because this would mean that the system is in the stable regime that
这意味着系统处于稳定状态
and the stable regime,
稳定的政权
if the arrival rate is slower,
如果到达速率较慢，
then the service capacity about how fast the set the request can be set.
服务能力指的是处理请求的速度有多快。
If you send more, obviously,
如果你发送更多的信息，显然，
the system will not be in a stable region,
系统将不会处于稳定状态。
which means that the queries,
这意味着查询，
the cure were growing different indefinitely,
治疗方法不断地不同地发展着。
right?
对的？
As more request comes in.
随着更多的请求到来。
And the subsystem cannot keep up with serving these requests.
子系统无法跟上处理这些请求的速度。
Okay?
好的？
All the results, typically,
通常情况下，所有的结果
in the queuing theory,
在排队论中，
assume that raw is great,
假设raw是很棒的，
is less than one.
小于一。
Then the parameters you have to compute is at times you spend in the queue.
你需要计算的参数是你在队列中花费的时间。
Do we know how long it takes a request to be settled?
我们知道一个请求需要多长时间才能解决吗？
He still is on the settle.
他仍然在安顿中。
So now we need to understand how long it takes a request to in
现在我们需要了解一个请求需要多长时间才能完成。
is going to spend in the queue.
将要在队列中花费的时间。
So then by adding that,
那么，通过添加那个，
do we know the service time for the queuing time?
我们知道排队时间的服务时间吗？
We know how much a request trend in the entire system,
我们知道整个系统中请求的趋势有多大。
which is what matters from the user perspective.
从用户的角度来看，这才是最重要的。
And then we also went to,
然后我们还去了，
we learn about the little law.
我们学习了利特尔定律。
The little law is allows you to compute the queue line of by
小定律允许你计算队列的长度。
just multiplying the mean arrival rate
只需将平均到达率相乘即可。
plus times this spending,
加上这笔支出，
the time times the time average time spent in the queue.
时间乘以平均排队时间，得到在队列中花费的平均时间。
This are some of the results we went over last time.
这是我们上次讨论过的一些结果。
Again.
再次。
This is a recap, which may help you for the tomorrow's midterm.
这是一个复习，可能会对你明天的期中考试有帮助。
Tq is for mmiq which is, remember,
Tq 是为了 mmiq，记住，
mmq is one of the simplest queues out there.
mmq 是最简单的队列之一。
It has one is for means that it has one server.
这句话的意思是它有一个服务器。
And the first time refers to the distribution of the arrival rate.
第一次指的是到达率的分布。
This means that into the intervals
这意味着将其分成间隔
between two consecutive requests arriving is exponentially distributed.
两个连续请求到达之间的时间间隔服从指数分布。
Or it's also called poisson distribution of the arrival rate.
或者也被称为泊松分布的到达率。
And also, the service time is exponentially distributed.
而且，服务时间是指数分布的。
It's, again, the time it takes the set of its exponentially distributed.
这是指它的指数分布集合所需的时间。
The formula here is the set of a times row over one minus row
这里的公式是 a 乘以行向量除以一减去行向量。
for a more general cure.
为了一个更普遍的解决方案。
Where is a serving time?
服务时间在哪里？
It's general.
这是一般的情况。
It just characterized by this c we know only about the square coefficient
这个特征只有这个c系数的平方项我们知道
of variance.
方差分析
You have a very similar formula.
你有一个非常相似的公式。
Only the second parameters in the formula is different.
公式中只有第二个参数不同。
But the real main point to notice about this formula are this last term,
但是关于这个公式真正需要注意的是最后一项，
which is rho over one or minus rho.
rho over one is equal to rho, while minus rho is equal to negative rho.
This capture what I said earlier,
这是我之前说的内容的概括。
that if raw is should be less than one,
如果原始值(raw)应该小于1，
that if it's equal or greater than one,
如果它等于或大于一，
then the system will not be in a stable region.
那么系统将不会处于稳定状态。
This is a plot showing you roughly how the response time
这是一个大致显示响应时间的图表。
and the service time is looking
服务时间正在查看中
versus a throughput or utilization versus row.
与吞吐量或利用率相比，与行数相比。
So on the x axis is basically row is from zero, say, to one.
在x轴上，基本上行从零到一。
And this is a response time.
这是一个响应时间。
The response time is a queuing time for the service time.
响应时间是服务时间的排队时间。
A as a role goes to on.
A作为一个角色继续前进。
This is going to be dominated by the queuing time,
这将主要受到排队时间的影响。
because the queuing time is going to grow.
因为排队时间会增长。
A one row gets close to one,
一行趋近于一。
then this goes to infinity.
那么这将趋向无穷大。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Now let's talk about how we are going to optimize the performance.
现在让我们来讨论一下如何优化性能。
What are the ways to optimize it?
有哪些优化的方法？
And this is what we are going to discuss over the next several slides.
接下来几张幻灯片我们将讨论的内容如下。
And again,
再一次，
if you look about io for an io device,
如果你在寻找关于IO设备的IO方面的信息，
you are going to have the user strategy.
你将要拥有用户策略。
This is where the program is running.
程序正在运行的地方。
Then you see, you are going to send requests,
那么你要发送请求，
say, read or write from this particular file,
操作这个特定文件，可以进行读取或写入操作。
which is from that part of one particular device.
这是来自某个特定设备的部分。
And these requests are cured,
这些请求已经处理完成，
then are submitted to a controller.
然后被提交给控制器。
And the controller is going to program the other device to read and write
控制器将编程其他设备进行读写操作。
the particular data,
特定的数据
how you are going to improve this system.
你打算如何改进这个系统。
There are a few ways, one speed, right?
有几种方法，其中一种是速度，对吗？
You can make everything faster.
你可以让一切变得更快。
Each of these components, you can make it faster.
你可以加快这些组件中的每一个速度。
You reduce the overhead of the context switching.
你减少了上下文切换的开销。
You have also some context switching here of the controller of the device
在这里还有一些设备控制器的上下文切换。
that I do buy a discreet
我确实购买了一个谨慎的东西。
or taste faster with a lower sick time.
或者以更快的速度品尝，并且病假时间更短。
Another way is parallel is is basically you can paralyze,
另一种方法是并行化，基本上你可以将其并行化。
you can have inside.
你可以进去。
You can have multiple queues.
你可以拥有多个队列。
If the queue of selection are expensive.
如果选择队列很昂贵。
Or instead of an aisle device,
或者，可以使用一个过道设备，
you may have a multiply a device.
你可能有一个多功能设备。
You can, for instance,
例如，你可以
probably you can have two disks,
可能你可以有两个硬盘，
and then you are going to strive the data across disks.
然后你将努力将数据分布在多个磁盘上。
So therefore,
因此，
or you just partition the data between disks,
或者你只需将数据在磁盘之间进行分区。
when different requests can run at the same time on,
当不同的请求可以同时运行时，
if they are going to request data on different disks,
如果他们要在不同的磁盘上请求数据，
then it's overlapped.
那么它就重叠了。
Right?
对吗？
And this applies to different parts of this kind of pipeline.
这适用于这种类型的流水线的不同部分。
For instance, for the thread,
例如，对于线程，
you send a request,
你发送了一个请求，
you are waiting for the request.
你正在等待请求。
You can do some useful work instead of just wait.
你可以做一些有用的工作，而不仅仅是等待。
The same thing here is like for the controller,
对于控制器来说，情况也是一样的。
as you program the current request and your programs that io device to ask
在编写当前请求和与I/O设备通信的程序时，请按照以下步骤进行操作。
three to satisfy the current request.
满足当前请求需要三个。
Once you do that and you send the request to our device,
一旦你完成这个操作并将请求发送到我们的设备上，
then you can process the next request.
那么你可以处理下一个请求。
The one important aspect here is that one way you to look at this pipeline,
这里的一个重要方面是你看待这个流水线的方式。
say you want to improve the performance here,
说你想要提高这里的性能，
what you are going to do,
你要做什么？
the engineering way to look about and or soft engineering way.
工程化的方式来看待和软件工程化的方式。
The sound way to do it is to look what is a bottlenecks are,
正确的做法是查看瓶颈所在。
which is a bottleneck,
哪个是瓶颈？
which is a slower spot in this chain,
在这个链条中，哪个环节是较慢的？
then you are going to focus on that bottleneck part to improve the performance.
那么你将专注于优化那个瓶颈部分以提高性能。
Because if you improve the performance of something which is already fast,
因为如果你提高已经很快的东西的性能，
not the slowest link on in the chain,
不是链条中最慢的环节，
then the engine performance will not improve much.
那么引擎性能不会有太大的改善。
Remember, the queues are here to absorb the burst.
记住，队列的作用是吸收突发的任务。
The queues is that because the requests are not going,
队列是因为请求没有进行。
where are equally distanced in time?
在时间上等距离的地方在哪里？
They can arrive a in aa bunch of requests at the same time.
他们可以同时到达一大批请求。
The controller cannot settle this bunch of requests at the same time.
控制器无法同时处理这一批请求。
So you need to incure them,
所以你需要承担它们的费用
because if they don't have a queue,
因为如果他们没有队列，
you need to drop on.
你需要放弃它。
The floor is request.
请按下电梯按钮。
You are going to fail satisfying these requests.
你将无法满足这些要求。
And finally, another things we didn't discuss last time,
最后，还有一些上次我们没有讨论到的事情。
it is one other techniques in these kind of systems.
这是这类系统中的另一种技术。
Its the admission control basically says, look,
这是关于准入控制的基本说法，它的意思是，看，
and it's an admission control.
这是一个入场控制。
Why you have a mission control in general,
为什么一般情况下会有一个任务控制中心？
is that you basically admission control say that I refuse to,
这基本上是说我拒绝接受你的入场控制。
i'm telling you this request I cannot handle.
我告诉你，我无法处理这个请求。
So the thread asked wants to submit a request and i'm saying the controller
所以线程要求提交一个请求，我正在说控制器。
or the queue itself,
或者队列本身，
saying I can no longer in queue this request on come later.
抱歉，我无法再将此请求排队，您可以稍后再来。
This also typically happens if we want to ensure to limit to provide
如果我们想确保限制提供，通常也会发生这种情况。
guarantees in terms
保证条款
of the or end to end latency,
端到端延迟的起始或结束部分
of end to end response time in order to provide.
为了提供端到端响应时间的准确性。
So basically saying, if i'm going to accept the request,
基本上就是说，如果我要接受这个请求，
i'm going to guarantee that i'm going to serve this request and say100 millisecond.
我将保证在100毫秒内完成这个请求。
Right?
对吗？
If I cannot,
如果我不能，
I if there is no admission controls and I cannot make that guarantee
如果没有入场控制，我无法保证。
because if there are a a lot of quest coming,
因为如果有很多问题到来，
which is exceeds the capacity of my system,
这超出了我的系统容量。
I cannot guarantee that each request is going to be processed within 100 millisecond.
我不能保证每个请求都能在100毫秒内处理完成。
Admission control.
入场控制。
Place is hand in hand with limiting the delay.
地点与限制延迟紧密相连。
If you want to have guarantees on the end to end delay.
如果你想要对端到端延迟有保证。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Can you give an example from real life where the admission control is employed?
可以给一个现实生活中使用入场控制的例子吗？
Any example,
任何例子，
the red lights on the entrance of the highway?
高速公路入口处的红灯？
That's exactly, that's a great example.
没错，这是个很好的例子。
And real time systems,
实时系统，
although I was that I wouldn't call it real timeline,
虽然我知道这并不是真正的时间线，但我不会称之为真实的时间线。
red lights on the entrance of the highway.
高速公路入口处的红灯。
That's a great example.
这是一个很好的例子。
And there are many other examples, like, for instance,
还有许多其他的例子，比如，
in during when there are more restriction on during covet during the pandemics,
在疫情期间，对于疫情期间的限制更加严格时，
some shops, you limit the number of customers who are inside.
有些商店会限制店内顾客的数量。
So in order to make sure that they can keep distance among themselves,
为了确保他们能够保持彼此之间的距离，
there are even more obvious examples.
还有更明显的例子。
Like when you fly on a plane,
就像你乘坐飞机时，
here is a mission control.
这是一个任务控制中心。
It's your seat, right?
这是你的座位，对吗？
You cannot.
你不能。
It's not like in a bus in which there is no mission control anyone can get in.
这不像在公交车上，没有任务控制，任何人都可以上车。
Ii guess it's a natural one,
我猜这是一种自然的现象。
no longer people who are no longer fit in a bus
不再适合乘坐公共汽车的人们
and that's a natural push back mechanism.
这是一种自然的反弹机制。
But there are many examples in real life when you are having this.
但在现实生活中有很多例子可以说明这一点。
So to speak admission control back like cross white list.
所谓的准入控制回到了类似于交叉白名单的方式。
That's a great one.
太棒了。
Richard, that's great.
Richard，太棒了。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
So any that is performance highest.
所以任何一个性能最高的。
Remember, obviously, one,
记住，显然，一个，
there are sequential reads where and this is sample.
这里有连续读取的地方，这是一个示例。
And we are going to see this is for the next few slides.
接下来几张幻灯片我们将会看到这个内容。
There is another one.
还有一个。
There is so much work.
工作量真的很大。
You get so many requests you can piggyback.
你收到了很多请求，你可以一起处理。
Basically, you can have so many requests,
基本上，你可以有很多请求，
but can the order the request says that you can serve
但是请求的顺序是否可以决定你能否提供服务？
this request much more effectively?
这个请求更有效吗？
We'll see that a lot a in a bit.
我们一会儿会看到很多这样的事情。
Now, if the system is mostly idle,
现在，如果系统大部分时间处于空闲状态，
it's perfectly fine to be inefficient.
效率低下是完全可以接受的。
No one cares, right?
没人在乎，对吧？
And burst.
并且爆发。
This is an important point, right?
这是一个重要的观点，对吗？
When you have a bust,
当你遇到困境时，
meaning that you get more requires and the system can handle.
意思是你会得到更多的需求，而系统可以处理。
So you need to choose us is boss's threat or should be threat there,
所以你需要选择我们是老板的威胁还是应该威胁我们。
because they can increase the latency, right?
因为它们可以增加延迟，对吗？
Because it increases requests.
因为它增加了请求。
But it's also an opportunity because you can do this figure backing you can.
但这也是一个机会，因为你可以做这个图形的支持。
Again, the audience, the request, as we'll see,
再次强调，观众，请求，正如我们将看到的，
in a few slides where you can do batching meetings,
在几张幻灯片中，您可以进行会议批处理。
you can, for instance,
例如，你可以
you have many requests.
你有很多请求。
You can go on context switching or a function calls.
你可以进行上下文切换或函数调用。
You can think about you can do one context switching to handle multiple
你可以考虑使用上下文切换来处理多个任务。
of these requests at the same time.
同时处理这些请求。
You are mortar is a context switching across multiple requests.
您的意思是"您的砂浆是在多个请求之间进行上下文切换"吗？
You can also waste the space for speed.
你也可以为了速度而浪费空间。
For instance, you can,
例如，你可以，
when you write on the disk,
当你向磁盘写入数据时，
like, let's see, what will be a a good examples.
好的，让我想想，有哪些好的例子呢。
You can have,
你可以拥有，
you can have,
for instance, for base tables.
例如，对于基本表。
For page tables, you can have additional hash maps,
对于页表，你可以有额外的哈希映射。
which are going to keep in order to locate to map
为了定位到地图上的位置，需要保留哪些信息？
the virtual pages to the page numbers to the physical page numbers.
将虚拟页映射到页号和物理页号。
Another way to do it is to increase the size of the tlb another way
另一种方法是增加 TLB 的大小。
to increase the performance in what you learn in,
提高你所学习的领域的表现
we learn in the past is to increase the cache size.
我们过去学到的是增加缓存大小。
In order to reduce to also improve the performance,
为了减少并提高性能，
but for improve system performance,
但是为了提高系统性能，
program performance,
程序性能
you can also increase the memory size.
你还可以增加内存大小。
There is a ballet anomaly with,
这里有一个芭蕾舞的异常情况。
as you now for a certain a patriots replacement of policies,
正如你所知，对于某个爱国者政策的替代方案，
increasing the size of the memory,
增加内存的大小
of the size of the cash,
现金的金额大小
doesn't necessarily reduce the number of false space faults.
并不一定减少虚假空间错误的数量。
But in general,
但是一般来说，
for many of these pay replacement policy,
对于许多这些支付替代政策来说，
like alu that's increasing the memory size,
像ALU这样的东西可以增加内存的大小，
always, really doesn't will likely decrease,
总是，真的不太可能减少。
most likely will decrease the number of page four.
很可能会减少第四页的数量。
You set a few examples where you can have increase the number of the space
你可以举几个例子来增加空间的数量。
to or increase the space and to improve the speed.
扩大空间并提高速度。
And other techniques are reduced overheads through user level drivers.
另外一种技术是通过用户级驱动程序减少开销。
So basically, if you can implement the function,
基本上，如果你能实现这个函数，
it is a user level,
这是一个用户级别的操作。
you may avoid the context switching because you don't need operating system
你可以避免上下文切换，因为你不需要操作系统。
in order to handle these requests.
为了处理这些请求。
And the other one is,
另一个是，
like I mentioned earlier,
正如我之前提到的，
the overlap.
重叠。
So are you goodbye while you are doing waiting for an hour to complete?
你是在等一个小时才能完成吗？那么你现在要离开了吗？
You are doing the useful of more useful work.
你正在做更有用的工作。
And this can happen in multiple levels.
这种情况可以发生在多个层次上。
It can happen in as your operating system when our operating system on a thread
当我们的操作系统在一个线程上运行时，这种情况可能会发生。
is blog on aiod by on io request,
这句话的意思是"在IO请求上，通过异步IO进行博客操作"。
is going to switch it out.
将要进行切换。
It putting the thread on the waiting queue and is going to schedule.
它将线程放入等待队列并准备进行调度。
The operating system is going to schedule a new thread,
操作系统将要调度一个新的线程。
which is on the ridicule.
这是荒谬的。
So now we are going to look into a beetle into the disk schedule,
现在我们要研究一下磁盘调度中的一种算法，叫做"beetle"。
right?
对的？
The disk, remember,
磁盘，记住，
is quite complicated.
相当复杂。
I do has multiple plates.
我确实有多个盘子。
Each place has two surfaces up, down,
每个地方有两个表面，上面和下面。
and then you have cylinders and sectors.
然后你有柱面和扇区。
So when a request comes in from the operating system to read or write
当操作系统发出读取或写入请求时
on the disk,
在磁盘上
is going to tell you,
将要告诉你，
typically is telling you what is a cylinder, the face,
通常会告诉你什么是圆柱体、面、
the surface,
表面
and what is the second.
第二个是什么？
Right?
对吗？
Here we are talking,
我们在这里交谈，
we are considering a similar example,
我们正在考虑一个类似的例子，
or you have the just a cylinder and the sector.
或者你只有一个圆柱和扇区。
Is this how the request to look like?
请求是这样的吗？
In this case,
在这种情况下，
you have two numbers for it requires a cylinder and the sector.
你需要提供两个数字，一个是柱面号，另一个是扇区号。
The request also is going to specify what is a read and write.
该请求还将指定什么是读和写操作。
And because this is slow,
而且由于这很慢，
more likely you are going to have some requests which are cute.
更有可能的是，你会收到一些可爱的请求。
Okay.
好的。
Now, the interesting aspect here,
现在，这里的有趣之处是，
the requests are, in general, are independent,
请求通常是独立的。
are in general independent.
一般来说是独立的。
So now the question is how you are going to serve this request?
现在的问题是你打算如何处理这个请求？
A simpler story is five,
一个更简单的故事是五个。
right?
对的吗？
You send the request in the order when you arrive.
您在到达时按顺序发送请求。
This is fair among the request that is fair with respect to the order
这是一个公平的请求，就顺序而言是公平的。
in the submit the request.
在提交请求中。
But it can be very long six.
但是六个可能会很长。
Why?
为了方便中文用户理解和使用，我将英文翻译成中文。这样可以提供更好的帮助和支持。
Because the head can go randomly from one cylinder or one track to another.
因为磁头可以随机地从一个柱面或一个磁道移动到另一个。
Right?
对吗？
You don't run that, because you remember the sick time is very expensive,
你不要运行它，因为你记得生病的时间是非常昂贵的。
as well, as, you know,
同样，就像你知道的那样，
rotational latency.
旋转延迟。
So you don't want to go to,
所以你不想去？
do you want to be smarter than that?
你想比那个更聪明吗？
That'll be a smart way to do it, right?
这是一个明智的做法，对吗？
If you want to minimize a sick time,
如果你想尽量减少生病的时间，
why is yourself a request?
为什么你是一个请求？
You are in a certain position on the disk.
你当前位于磁盘上的某个位置。
You want to look in the cure and take the request.
你想查看疗程并接受请求。
It's closest to you,
它离你最近，
because if the request is closest to you,
因为如果请求离您最近，
are going to minimize the sector.
你们打算将扇区最小化。
This is short a 6 time.
这是第6次短暂的。
First, right?
首先，对吗？
You pick the request that it closes to the head on the disk.
你选择离磁盘头最近的请求进行处理。
In general,
一般来说，
you also need to include the rotational delay,
你还需要考虑旋转延迟。
not only the sick time,
不仅仅是病假时间，
but for now, let's simplify it only to sick time.
但现在，让我们只把它简化为病假时间。
So now the sick will reduce the time if you look.
所以现在如果你看的话，病人的时间会减少。
But what is not good?
但是什么不好？
It's got mainly to starvation.
这主要是由于饥饿引起的。
Like, for instance,
例如，
if a lot of requests come and they are clustered close by,
如果有很多请求同时到达且它们在空间上聚集在一起，
then according to these disciplines,
根据这些规定，
you are shorter, sick time.
你身材较矮，生病时间较长。
First, you are going to serve this request and the request,
首先，您需要处理此请求和请求内容。
which is farther a lot,
哪个更远很多，
which is a farmer.
这是一个农民。
Like for instance,
例如，
at the edge of the disk,
在磁盘的边缘位置，
may wait for a long time to be service.
可能需要很长时间才能得到服务。
Make sense?
有意义吗？
So you're downtown that.
所以你在市中心那里。
So again,
所以再次，
greater very sick time, but it's unfair.
非常不幸，生病的时间更长了，但这是不公平的。
Can cause salvation.
可以带来拯救。
One solution to that is cap.
其中一个解决方案是使用容量限制。
It's a pretty nice solution.
这是一个相当不错的解决方案。
These are what you see here.
这些是你在这里看到的。
These numbers think about.
这些数字让人思考。
These are trucks or cylinders.
这些是卡车或圆柱体。
Right?
对吗？
A cylinder is all the tracks,
一个柱面是所有的磁道，
which are under the heads on different bladders.
这些位于不同膀胱上的头部下方。
So scan is basically you start going into one direction,
扫描基本上是你开始朝一个方向前进，
either to the issues of the disk or to the inside of the disk.
可能是与磁盘的问题有关，也可能是与磁盘内部有关。
You are only going to set the request in the direction you are going.
你只需要将请求设置为你要前往的方向。
Right?
对吗？
You send the request on, say,
你可以将请求发送出去，比如说，
track 53.
第53轨道。
Then you look in the queue and you have multiple requests,
然后你查看队列，发现有多个请求。
say you pick the one which is closest to you in the direction you are going
选择离你当前行进方向最近的一个。
is 3037.
是3037。
Then the next one,
接下来的一个是，
it's 14 and so forth.
这是14，等等。
And in these times, for instance,
在这些时候，例如，
if when yourself the request 53,
如果当你自己请求53时，
you get the request 65.
你收到了请求 65。
This is closest to you according to the shelter 6 time first yourself,
根据庇护所的时间表，这是离你最近的时间。请先自己确认一下。
this request,
这个请求，
because it's not in the request on track 65 is not in the direction
因为在轨道65上的请求没有在指定的方向上。
of your movement.
您的移动方式。
You are going to ignore it.
你将会忽略它。
You go until the last request in your direction,
你一直进行，直到你所负责的最后一个请求。
and then after reverse,
然后在反转之后，
here, I say, no starvation,
我在这里说，没有饥饿现象。
but still retain a flavor of shortest 6 times.
但仍保留了最短的6倍的特点。
First.
首先。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
Tell me why is that?
告诉我为什么会这样？
Why do we still have a problem with this one with cap?
为什么我们在这个带有容量限制的问题上仍然存在困扰？
By the way,
顺便说一下，
it's called elevator algorithm.
它被称为电梯算法。
Can you think about that scan?
你能考虑一下那个扫描吗？
Excavate any unfairness.
挖掘出任何不公平之处。
And why?
为什么？
If
如果
I listen to say you may never embarrasses,
我听说你可能从不尴尬
does keep arriving at the same spot.
不断到达相同的位置。
So basically on the same track, that's true.
基本上是在同一个轨道上，没错。
That's a pretty edge case.
这是一个非常特殊的情况。
It's a good asset,
这是一个很好的资产。
but it's a little bit edge.
但这有点边缘。
What else can you think about some other requests which will get preferential
还有哪些其他请求可能会得到优先处理？
treatment if they are in some region of the disk versus others.
对于磁盘的不同区域，它们的处理方式也会有所不同。
Carol, ask a question,
Carol，你有问题吗？
how do we define the initial direction for a scan?
我们如何定义扫描的初始方向？
I guess I it's a good question.
我猜这是一个很好的问题。
I think ii don't know,
我想我不知道。
but I don't think it matters.
但我认为这并不重要。
You can,
你可以。
you can choose any anyone initially?
你可以最初选择任何一个吗？
Yeah.
是的。
There is more data on the outer rings.
外环上有更多的数据。
So traveling,
旅行，
it's favored.
它受到青睐。
Yeah,
是的，
you are, right?
是的，我是。
It's like, let me see.
就像，让我看看。
It's also a question here.
这里也有一个问题。
It's the same question.
这是同一个问题。
So carl, it's, again, the answer to your question.
所以卡尔，这是你的问题的答案。
I already find the initial directions.
我已经找到了初始的指示。
I think it doesn't matter.
我认为这没关系。
You can,
你可以。
but I I do not know,
但是我不知道。
and I don't see a reason.
我看不出有任何理由。
So that's very important.
所以这非常重要。
Going back now,
现在返回，
it is going back about when this scan is not fair.
当这个扫描不公平时，它会退回去。
So hearing one is not fair,
所以听一个是不公平的，
which requests are fate out of for each request,
每个请求中有哪些是命运的？
thus can provide advantage, favor them.
因此可以提供优势，对他们有利。
So here the request in the middle,
所以在这里是请求的中间部分，
you get quicker to the request in the middle.
你在中间的请求上更快地响应。
Right?
对吗？
Like, for instance, I can't go to a request.
比如，我无法处理一个请求。
I say it takes1 million seconds to go from one and to another.
我说从一个地方到另一个地方需要100万秒。
Right?
对吗？
If I missed a request, arrives here,
如果我错过了一个请求，它会到达这里。
just after the scan has passed in that direction, just I missed it.
就在扫描朝那个方向通过后，我刚刚错过了它。
I say, goes 0.5 million seconds to one.
我说，0.5百万秒等于多少。
And I know it turns 0.5 million seconds to come to me.
我知道它需要500,000秒才能到达我这里。
I wait for 1 millisecond.
我等待1毫秒。
But if this happens when i'm at the edge,
但如果这发生在我处于边缘的时候，
so I just missed the hat which now goes towards the inside of the disk,
所以我刚刚错过了帽子，现在它朝向磁盘的内部。
then you have to wait for 2 millisecond.
那么你需要等待2毫秒。
Need to wait 1 millisecond to go all the way to the inside
需要等待1毫秒才能完全进入内部。
and 1 millisecond to go back.
并且需要1毫秒返回。
Again, I am over simplifying things here,
再次强调，我在这里过于简化了事情。
but just give you a sense.
但只是给你一个概念。
So scan favors the request which are in the middle,
因此，扫描算法更倾向于处理位于中间的请求。
right?
对的？
And not the request which are at the edges.
而不是位于边缘的请求。
What is the solution here?
这里的解决方案是什么？
While the solution is circular scan or the sea scan?
解决方案是循环扫描还是海扫描？
This basically just go one direction.
这基本上只是朝一个方向前进。
So say, go always,
所以说，继续前进，
you sell the request only in one direction.
你只提供单向的请求。
When you are done,
完成后，
results immediately go to all the other age and start serving them again.
结果立即传递给所有其他年龄段，并重新开始为它们提供服务。
That's kind of what it is.
这有点像是这样的。
But I say, if I missed, if I request,
但是我说，如果我错过了，如果我请求，
I just misses the head.
我刚刚错过了头部。
No matter what the request is,
无论请求是什么，
on the average,
平均而言，
is going to wait for the same time for the hat to come to be back,
将等待相同的时间，直到帽子回来。
to be self.
成为自我。
This is not biased towards the pages in the middle.
这不对中间的页面有偏见。
Finally, I mentioned that you can hide the latency.
最后，我提到你可以隐藏延迟。
How do you hide the io latency?
如何隐藏IO延迟？
If the blocking interface is a way to already discussed,
如果阻塞接口已经讨论过的话，
you have a block,
你有一个块。
read and write,
读和写
system call, you put process operating system,
系统调用，是将进程操作系统的一种方式。
put processors to sleep until the data is ready.
将处理器置于休眠状态，直到数据准备就绪。
The request is served.
请求已处理。
And during this time,
在此期间，
the operating system schedules,
操作系统进行调度，
tasks already tasks,
任务已经完成。
which out of can use acpu non blocking interfaces?
哪些接口可以使用非阻塞方式使用CPU？
Don't wait.
不要等待。
Basically, this, you remember,
基本上，这个，你记得的，
this is a interface in which are just going to issues and requests.
这是一个界面，只用于发布问题和请求。
But then returns immediately.
但是立即返回。
You just after you return, you do something else.
你刚回来后，你可以做其他事情。
Right?
对吗？
Then later you need to go and see whether you got the data or
然后稍后你需要去查看你是否收到了数据。
you wrote the data to the canon.
你将数据写入了佳能相机。
I synchronous interface is stimulated.
同步接口被激活。
Again, it's like in the non blocking interface,
再次强调，就像在非阻塞接口中一样，
it returns immediately the request,
它立即返回请求。
because in this case, for instance,
因为在这种情况下，例如，
when you get the data,
当你获取到数据时，
you allocate the buffer,
你分配缓冲区，
you give the pointer as a buffer.
你将指针作为缓冲区。
And there is a operating system,
还有一个操作系统，
basically put the data when available starting from this pointer,
基本上，从这个指针开始，将数据放入当数据可用时。
right in the buffer.
在缓冲区中。
And then let me know when you send the data is the same.
然后在你发送数据时，请告诉我数据是否相同。
Right?
对吗？
You are going to create a buffer.
你将要创建一个缓冲区。
You are going there,
你要去那里。
you are going to want,
你会想要的。
you are where you put the data or you want to send,
你是指你想要存储或发送数据的位置吗？
then you give to the kernel to the os in the right operation,
然后你将正确的操作传递给操作系统的内核。
in the right system call,
在正确的系统调用中，
you gives a pointer of the buffer you want to be transferred.
你提供了一个要传输的缓冲区的指针。
So now recall the entire era here for the aisle.
现在回忆一下整个时代，为过道做准备。
This is a top part,
这是一个顶部部分。
a which appraisal pre,
一项评估前的准备工作
which provides api and the abstraction to the applications.
它提供了应用程序的API和抽象层。
Whether it's streams or it's a block,
无论是流还是块，
api plus the system calls open,
API加上系统调用open，
read, write, and clouds.
读取、写入和云存储。
Then at the bottom were so covered.
然后底部被完全覆盖了。
Last time.
上次。
This is about aisle drivers, controllers, right?
是的，这是关于过道驱动程序和控制器的问题。
These are the drivers which are interacting with the physical device.
这些是与物理设备进行交互的驱动程序。
Read and write the data to the physical device.
将数据读取和写入物理设备。
The middle is a system which kind of makes a conversion, in some sense,
中间是一种系统，从某种意义上说，它进行了一种转换。
from the api which is provided to the application by the operating system.
通过操作系统提供给应用程序的API。
And the api of the aisle driver,
走廊驱动程序的API
which is a block interface in general,
一般情况下，块接口是什么？
more precisely,
更准确地说，
for the api for the higher level for the application.
用于应用程序的更高级别的API。
You typically have a variable size buffer for the file system,
通常情况下，文件系统会使用可变大小的缓冲区。
which are going to talk more about this.
将要更多地讨论这个话题。
You are going to have blocks,
你将会拥有一些数据块。
but the blocks are logically indexed.
但是这些块是逻辑上索引的。
These are where the data is stored,
这些是数据存储的位置，
right?
对的？
Logically indexed,
逻辑索引化
meaning that the index in the operating system is not the same index,
意思是操作系统中的索引与原索引不同。
which of that block on the physical device.
这个块位于物理设备上的哪个位置？
This is done by the harder device and by their controllers,
这是由更复杂的设备和它们的控制器完成的。
mapping from this block device,
从这个块设备的映射
from the operating system to the blocks,
从操作系统到块
all the sectors on the harvey stripes.
哈维条纹上的所有扇区。
Remember that the blocks in the operating system are typically have
请记住，操作系统中的块通常是具有以下特点的：
like 20 four kilobytes.
像是20个四千字节。
And sectors on the hardest drives are smaller.
硬盘上的扇区更小。
There are 512 bytes.
有512字节。
So you have typical, you can have eight sectors for each,
所以你有典型的情况，每个可以有八个扇区。
but a block requires eight sectors.
但是一个块需要八个扇区。
And you have an ssd you remember,
你有一个固态硬盘，你记得吗？
you have these flash translation layers,
你有这些闪存转换层。
which again, maps a logical index of the blocks to the physical blocks.
再次，它将块的逻辑索引映射到物理块。
That's pretty much what you have and also have your asian pages.
这基本上就是你所拥有的，还有你的亚洲页面。
Let's look, now we are going to start looking more a little bit,
让我们来看看，现在我们要开始更仔细地看一下，
more depths to the file system.
更深入的文件系统。
One way to define it, like I mentioned,
一种定义它的方法，就像我之前提到的，
it's a layer of the operating system that maps is
这是操作系统的一层，用于映射
the api provided to the application,
提供给应用程序的API
which is files,
这是文件。
directories,
目录
a stream of bytes into lower level,
将字节流转换为较低级别的数据
api of the io devices,
输入/输出设备的API
which is a block interface.
这是一个块接口。
There are a few things here.
这里有几件事情。
This needs to be done the operating system.
这需要在操作系统中完成。
And that's naming,
这就是命名。
you need to find file by name.
你需要根据文件名查找文件。
You don't give to the osa block where the data is.
你没有给出数据所在的osa块。
You let operating system worry about mapping between the file name and the block.
你让操作系统来处理文件名和块之间的映射。
This is part of the organization.
这是组织的一部分。
Also part of the organization is about the file names are typically within directories.
组织的一部分还涉及文件名通常位于目录中。
So you need also to locate the file name within a particular directory,
所以你还需要在特定目录中定位文件名。
also need to provide protection.
还需要提供保护措施。
We enforce access restriction.
我们执行访问限制。
When do you do that?
你什么时候做那件事？
When you open the file?
你什么时候打开这个文件？
Typically?
通常情况下？
Those finally reliability,
最终的可靠性，
why do you still store the data on the disk?
为什么你们仍然将数据存储在磁盘上？
Because it's durable.
因为它耐用。
You want to survive data to survive when there are crashes or when
当发生崩溃或断电时，您希望数据能够存活下来。
your laptop is followed out.
你的笔记本电脑坏了。
So from the user perspective,
从用户的角度来看，
then I have some data structures which I want to restore
那么我有一些数据结构需要恢复
those data structure beautifully.
那些数据结构设计得非常优雅。
That's what I want as a user.
作为用户，这正是我想要的。
That was a file system.
那是一个文件系统。
I should offer me.
我应该提供自己。
Now, from the system views,
现在，从系统的角度来看，
i'm talking here about the call interface.
我在这里谈论的是调用接口。
The api is the boundary of the boundary between the operating system and
API是操作系统和应用程序之间的边界。
the user face.
用户界面。
The system sees what it doesn't have any idea about what data structure
系统看到了它对数据结构一无所知
the application has.
该应用程序具有。
It just see a bunch of bites,
它只是看到一堆字节。
a collection of bites,
一组字节
the system of then it has needs to take this collection of bytes,
然后系统需要将这些字节进行处理。
this bunch of bytes and write them on the this device,
将这一串字节写入该设备。
on the device hardest drive.
在设备的硬盘上。
Then the system view that it's inside the kernel.
然后系统视图是在内核中。
This is the one which interfaces to the devices.
这是与设备进行接口的部分。
It takes a collection of block,
它接受一个块的集合。
and it sees a collection of,
它看到了一组，
instead of takes a collection of bytes and map them to a collection of blocks.
不再接收一系列字节并将其映射为一系列块。
The collection of blocks are still logically identified.
这些块的集合仍然在逻辑上被标识。
Logically, again,
再次逻辑上来说，
means that is either identification is not the physical identification,
意味着身份识别不是指物理识别，
or these blocks are on the disk.
或者这些块在磁盘上。
And like I mentioned,
正如我之前提到的，
the block size is typically greater than sector size.
块大小通常大于扇区大小。
Let's see what happens when, for instance,
让我们看看当某种情况发生时会发生什么，例如，
the user says to the operating system,
用户对操作系统说，
I want buys between 2 and 12 from this file.
我想从这个文件中购买2到12之间的物品。
The operating system has to face the block corresponding to those bytes,
操作系统必须面对与这些字节对应的块。
and just returns the correct portion to the operating system to the application.
并且只将正确的部分返回给操作系统，再返回给应用程序。
What about on the right by two between two and 12?
在右边，从2到12之间的位置呢？
You fetch the block from the disk.
你从磁盘中获取数据块。
You modify the relevant portion,
你需要修改相关部分，
and you write down the block, the block.
你把块写下来，块。
So you take for writing these 10 bytes,
所以你需要写入这10个字节，
you get the block,
你获得了这个块。
which is four kilobytes,
这是四千字节。
update these 10 bytes,
更新这10个字节。
and then ride back the four kilobytes.
然后将四千字节的数据传送回来。
So every sink between the operating system and the devices is a block ground.
所以操作系统和设备之间的每个接口都是一个块接地。
Large.
大的。
Therefore, if you you all always are going to pay the overhead of reading
因此，如果你们总是要承担阅读的开销
and writing blocks as a blog analytic.
并将写作块作为博客分析。
So let's it's again a file system.
所以让我们再来说一下文件系统。
You have directories and files.
你有目录和文件。
Director, you can think about that the user visible index,
主管，您可以考虑一下用户可见的索引，
mapping names to files.
将名称映射到文件。
And the disk is just a linear of array of sectors.
而磁盘只是一个扇区的线性数组。
You can look, right?
你可以看，对吗？
It's a sectors on,
这是一个扇区上的问题。
you have a bunch of sectors on a track.
你在一条磁道上有一堆扇区。
You have a bunch of tracks on a face of a bladder.
你在膀胱的一个表面上有一堆轨道。
And then for each bladder,
然后对于每个膀胱，
you have two faces.
你有两个面孔。
And then for a harvest drive,
然后进行一次收获驱动活动，
you have multiple bladders.
你有多个膀胱。
Therefore, a sector is defined by,
因此，一个扇区的定义是，
like I mentioned earlier on,
就像我之前提到的那样，
by the cylinder,
按照柱面
the surface, and the sector.
表面和扇区。
Now, the main.protects from this slide,
现在，main.protects 从这个幻灯片中保护。
and it's re emphasizing what I said earlier on is that in the operating system
这再次强调了我之前所说的，在操作系统中。
doesn't track at the level,
不在该级别进行跟踪
the sector using their physical identifier.
使用物理标识符来定位扇区。
The physical identifier.
物理标识符。
Again, here is a cylinder surface and sector on the disk.
这是一个磁盘上的圆柱体表面和扇区。
Instead, you have a logical block addressing.
相反，你有一个逻辑块地址。
And typically,
通常情况下，
now the controller translate this logical block addressing
现在控制器将这个逻辑块地址进行翻译。
to the physical block addressing is something similar.
对于物理块寻址，有类似的方法。
A with virtual addresses,
带有虚拟地址的A，
the way that the operating system is responsible for translating.
操作系统负责翻译的方式。
The virtual address is the physical addresses.
虚拟地址是物理地址。
A it's a good.
这是很好的。
Let me ask answer this question from allison.
让我来回答Allison的问题。
Why don't we build devices and let us go lower?
为什么我们不构建设备，让我们的技术更加先进？
Basically, ii guess,
基本上，我猜
lower the priority of rights and rights?
降低权限和权利的优先级？
I guess this is a very good question,
我觉得这是一个非常好的问题，
and the answer is the overhead.
答案是开销。
So you are correct.
所以你是正确的。
Allison,
艾莉森，
this is because efficiency.
这是因为效率。
Remember, again, just think about the hardest drives.
记住，再次思考一下最困难的驱动器。
If you remember, the hardest drives.
如果你还记得的话，是指最难的驱动器。
In the last lecture,
在上一堂课中，
there is some example.
这里有一些例子。
The seek and rotational latency were like89 million seconds.
寻道和旋转延迟大约为8900万秒。
The time to transfer a block,
传输一个数据块所需的时间，
even if the block or as a sector,
即使是作为一个块或扇区，
even if the sector is 500, 12 bytes,
即使扇区大小为500，每个扇区12字节，
is not only 1 byte,
不仅仅是1个字节。
was much less than only second.
远远不及仅仅是第二名。
So the time to transfer to randomly access and transfer a sector is dwarfed
因此，随机访问和传输一个扇区所需的时间微不足道。
by the rotation latency,
通过旋转延迟，
by the fixed overhead.
通过固定开销。
Let a rotation latency and seek that.
让我们来解释一下旋转延迟和寻道时间。
So is that because of that is always an overhead?
那是因为它总是有额外开销的原因吗？
Another way to think about is here it is another way to think about.
另一种思考方式是这样的，这是另一种思考方式。
And maybe let me just and to connect the dots here.
或许让我来串联一下这些点吧。
Remember this slide.
记住这张幻灯片。
Look here at this formula.
看这个公式。
The smaller the bees,
蜜蜂越小，
the less the effective bandwidth is.
带宽越小，效率越低。
If b is very small,
如果b非常小，
s will dominate the fixed overhead.
固定开销将主导。
This is just overhead.
这只是额外开销。
It's useless work.
这是无用的工作。
And the smaller the bees,
蜜蜂越小，
the lower the effective bandwidth is,
有效带宽越低，
look at the red curve here.
看一下这里的红色曲线。
So that's what you have.
那就是你所拥有的。
Each request, pressing each request as a fixed overhead.
每个请求，将每个请求视为固定开销。
Even if this is on,
即使这个开着，
let me go here.
让我去这里。
Even if these devices is solid,
即使这些设备是坚固的，
its ssd not this drive.
是固态硬盘（SSD），不是这个驱动器。
There is an overhead for controller,
控制器有一定的开销。
is an overhead or contact switching and things like that.
是一种开销或接触切换等操作。
Okay, hopefully answer your questions.
好的，希望能回答你的问题。
Okay, let's go back.
好的，让我们回到之前的话题。
What do you need for file system needs?
文件系统需要什么？
What do you know if you design a file system?
如果你设计一个文件系统，你需要了解以下内容：
1. 文件系统的基本概念：了解文件系统的定义、功能和特性，以及文件和目录的组织结构。
2. 存储管理：了解如何管理文件在存储介质上的存储和访问，包括磁盘分区、块分配和文件的物理存储。
3. 文件操作：了解如何创建、打开、读取、写入、关闭和删除文件，以及文件的权限和保护机制。
4. 目录管理：了解如何创建、删除和重命名目录，以及如何在目录中组织和管理文件。
5. 文件系统的一致性和恢复：了解如何确保文件系统的一致性，包括事务处理、日志记录和崩溃恢复。
6. 文件系统的性能优化：了解如何提高文件系统的性能，包括缓存、预读取、延迟分配和空间回收等技术。
7. 文件系统的安全性：了解如何保护文件系统的安全性，包括访问控制、加密和防止数据丢失或损坏的措施。
8. 文件系统的扩展性：了解如何设计一个可扩展的文件系统，以适应不断增长的存储需求。
9. 文件系统的兼容性：了解如何设计一个与现有操作系统和应用程序兼容的文件系统。
10. 文件系统的测试和调试：了解如何测试和调试文件系统，以确保其正确性和稳定性。
设计一个文件系统需要综合考虑以上各个方面，并根据具体需求和限制做出相应的设计决策。
Or do you need to be careful about?
或者你需要小心些吗？
You need basically to track which for a file,
你基本上需要追踪一个文件的哪些内容。
which are the blocks containing the data from that file,
哪些块包含了该文件的数据？
you need to track it.
你需要追踪它。
You need to for a particular file,
你需要查找一个特定的文件。
you need to now to know which directory contains it.
你需要知道它所在的目录。
And then you need to track the few free disk blocks,
然后你需要跟踪少量的空闲磁盘块。
because if you write something new in a file,
因为如果你在文件中写入新内容，
you need to know which blocks are free, are empty.
你需要知道哪些块是空闲的，是空的。
And then you also need to decide or to maintain this information.
然后你还需要决定或维护这些信息。
And the answer this information has to be persistent,
而且这些信息的答案必须是持久的。
because it's persistent.
因为它是持久的。
You have to maintain it on the disk.
你需要将它保存在磁盘上。
So it's, again,
所以，再次，
data structures on the disk is different from the data structure in memory.
磁盘上的数据结构与内存中的数据结构是不同的。
The application, you have a data structure.
这个应用程序中有一个数据结构。
The disk, or even the operating system is unaware,
磁盘甚至操作系统本身都不知道
completely oblivious about the data structure you have in your program.
完全不知道你程序中的数据结构。
It just sees a bunch of bytes,
它只是看到一堆字节。
and later, a bunch of blocks.
然后，一堆块。
That's what it is.
就是这样。
Again, because you access a block at a time,
由于您一次访问一个块，所以
is not very existing.
不是非常存在。
Access are not very efficient for when you access just a bite.
当你只访问一个字节时，访问速度并不高效。
And obviously,
显然，
like I mentioned,
就像我之前提到的那样，
when you write to a disk,
当你向磁盘写入数据时，
you expect to be durable.
你期望它具有耐久性。
That's why you write to a disk.
这就是为什么要将数据写入磁盘。
Otherwise you keep the things in memory.
否则，你将把这些东西保存在内存中。
But here you need to be careful.
但是在这里你需要小心。
You cannot assume that if you write or disk,
你不能假设如果你写入或读取磁盘，
if you say I wrote,
如果你说我写了，
ii call a right operation.
我调用了一个正确的操作。
Everything is fine.
一切都好。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
Tell me why if I just call the right operation to a five,
告诉我，如果我只是对一个数字五调用正确的操作，为什么会这样？
I cannot be completely sure that the date I wrote has been
我无法完全确定我写的日期是否准确。
stored durably on the disk.
持久地存储在磁盘上。
If you remember, we discussed early on about buffer cash.
如果你还记得的话，我们之前讨论过缓冲现金。
The data is not stored directly on the disk is stored in a buffer.
数据不直接存储在磁盘上，而是存储在缓冲区中。
If after you submit the request,
如果在您提交请求之后，
the obligation fails,
义务失败
the operating system fails.
操作系统失败。
The data may be lost.
数据可能会丢失。
Right?
对吗？
You need to call.
你需要打电话。
What do you need to call in order to make sure the data when goes to the risk?
为了确保数据在传输过程中不受风险影响，您需要调用什么？
What system called you are going to invoke flush.
你要调用哪个系统来执行 flush 操作？
Very good.
非常好。
Although I would wish also to have more people answering these questions.
虽然我希望有更多的人来回答这些问题。
So again,
所以再次，
it's not a wrong answer.
这不是一个错误的答案。
It's about discussing it.
这是关于讨论它的事情。
And you'll remember much easier if we have this kind of discussions
如果我们进行这种讨论，你会更容易记住。
rather than me just talking and talking and talking and being boring.
与其我一直在说个不停，让人感到无聊，不如...
So,
所以，
okay,
好的，没问题。
a few announcements very well.
一些公告非常好。
Tomorrow this is 11:03.
明天是11点03分。
Let me just think tomorrow we have the exam.
让我想一想，明天我们有考试。
I wish you the best of luck.
祝你好运。
All the materials is up to and included the last lecture, not this lecture,
所有的材料都是截止到上一堂课的，不包括本次课程。
the project deadline,
项目截止日期
it was pushed.
已经被推送。
So now you have a little bit, more time.
现在你有一点点更多的时间了。
So hopefully this really helps you.
希望这真的对你有所帮助。
Okay?
好的？
Again, let's go delete,
再次，让我们去删除，
even deeper talking about the file system.
更深入地讨论文件系统。
So again, a few core elements,
所以，再次强调，有几个核心要素，
the file system design,
文件系统设计
if you are talking about the performance,
如果你在谈论性能，
the dominant factor, remember,
主导因素，记住，
you are talking about.
你在说什么？
This is a bottleneck.
这是一个瓶颈。
The bottleneck a is a disk performance.
瓶颈是磁盘性能。
The disk was better provide the best performance when we
在我们使用时，磁盘提供了最佳的性能。
sequentially read and write data,
顺序读取和写入数据
because we avoid sick times,
因为我们要避免生病的时间。
and rotational latency is you're going to maximize these operations.
而旋转延迟是你要最大化这些操作的关键。
Remember, we can,
记住，我们可以，
it's a file systems,
这是一个文件系统。
abstraction provided in unix.
在Unix中提供的抽象化。
You need to its open, close,
你需要打开它，关闭它。
and in between read, write,
在读取和写入之间，
you cannot read and write to a disk without a file system,
没有文件系统，你无法读写磁盘。
without a file,
没有文件，
without opening and closing that file.
在不打开和关闭该文件的情况下。
The cool thing about this is that you can perform the protection, checks,
这个很酷的地方是你可以执行保护、检查操作，
admission,
录取
control,
控制，掌控，控制权
and or at the open.
在打开时。
When you open the file.
当您打开文件时。
Otherwise you'd have to check for protection.
否则你就需要检查保护机制。
Every time you access that file,
每次访问该文件时，
the size of the file is variable.
文件的大小是可变的。
When you start writing,
当你开始写作时，
you start this one block.
你开始这个块。
We need more than and one sector.
我们需要不止一个扇区。
We need more.
我们需要更多。
You are going, the file system is going to allocate more.
系统将要分配更多的文件系统空间。
So you don't need to predefine.
所以你不需要预先定义。
This is very important.
这非常重要。
You take it as a giver,
你把它当作一个给予者，
But it's not another design is like,
但它并不是另一种设计，就像这样，
you would just allocate space on the disk.
你只需要在磁盘上分配空间。
And before you start,
在你开始之前，
right?
对的？
And why is that natural?
为什么这是自然的呢？
It can be natural,
它可以是自然的，
because how do you do it in when in in your favorite programming language
因为你最喜欢的编程语言中如何实现这个功能？
like c right?
像 C 一样吗？
How do you manipulate the memory?
你如何操作内存？
How do you manipulate the storage of memory?
你如何操作内存的存储？
Before you read,
阅读之前，
or before you write some data?
还是在写入数据之前？
What do you need to?
你需要什么帮助？
Do?
做什么？
You need to allocate memory?
你需要分配内存吗？
I'm a lock or see a lock.
我是一个锁或者看到一个锁。
You allocate first,
你先分配
and then write.
然后写下来。
Here is not needed.
这里不需要。
You just write the operating system and the file system, in particular,
你只需要编写操作系统和文件系统，特别是：
will take care of growing the size of the file is needed.
如果需要的话，会负责增加文件的大小。
The files are organizing directory.
这些文件是组织目录。
You have a directory structured and these directory structure,
你有一个目录结构和这些目录结构。
the date the directories is and file.
目录和文件的日期。
It's also stored on the disk.
它也存储在磁盘上。
And then you need to allocate when you allocate fire,
然后当你分配火时，你需要进行分配。
when you allocate.
当你分配内存时。
I think we are going to see that in the next lecture,
我认为我们将在下一堂课中看到这一点。
when we allocate there are more sectors on the disk,
当我们分配空间时，磁盘上会有更多的扇区。
you want to allocate them continuously.
你想要连续地分配它们。
Why is that?
为什么这样做呢？
Because when you read the data,
因为当你读取数据时，
if the data was written on a bunch of sectors which is contiguous,
如果数据被连续写入一组扇区中，
you maximize the sequential access is,
你要最大化顺序访问。
right?
是的，正确的。
Sequential read in this case,
在这种情况下，进行顺序读取，
which improve the performance.
这将提高性能。
So here, how things look like under the hood a little bit?
这里，我们来稍微了解一下底层的情况是怎样的？
On one at one end,
在一端上，
you I have the file pass which is the file pass,
你好，我有一个名为"pass"的文件，这个文件是密码文件。
is a name of the file prefect prefix by the directory past name,
文件名是否由目录前缀和过去的名称完美前缀
whether that or the files is residing in which the directory pass.
无论是哪个文件还是目录路径中的文件，都需要确定它们所在的位置。
On the other end,
另一方面，
you have data blocks which are stored on the disc in sectors.
你有存储在磁盘扇区中的数据块。
You need somehow to map from the file pass to the data blocks.
你需要以某种方式将文件路径映射到数据块。
This is what the operating system file system is involved.
这是操作系统文件系统所涉及的内容。
You take the file pass.
你拿走了文件的密码。
It is going to point in some directory structure.
它将指向某个目录结构。
You are going to find the file.
你要找到这个文件。
The file is going to be as you are going to identify by a number.
该文件将通过一个编号进行标识。
It's called I number.
它被称为I号。
And this I number is going to point to us data structure,
而这个数字将指向我们的数据结构。
which is called I note,
它被称为I笔记
which repeat which contains all the the informations about that file,
其中包含有关该文件的所有信息的重复部分。
like for permissions, protection, permissions,
像权限、保护、权限这样的东西。
also information about the blocks or the data in the file is stored.
还存储了关于文件中的块或数据的信息。
This is the I node.
这是 I 节点。
Here is another view you remember about this.
这是你对此事的另一个观点。
So he had many lectures ago.
他在很多讲座之前提到过这个。
This is a view from the process perspective.
这是从进程角度的视角。
Here you have a process,
这里有一个进程，
you have threads, registers,
你有线程、寄存器、
and you have the address space.
你拥有地址空间。
Then when you open a file,
然后当你打开一个文件时，
you get the file descriptors points to a data structure here,
在这里，你获得了指向一个数据结构的文件描述符指针。
which is in the operating summits.
这是在操作峰会中。
Really, at the end of the day,
说实话，到了最后，
you are going to have the I note.
你将要拿到I笔记。
But anyway, the file description here,
但无论如何，这里是文件的描述：
in this case, you have a file name,
在这种情况下，你有一个文件名。
and you have position what the position in the file,
你需要确定文件中的位置。
what is the position you are going to read and write?
你将要读取和写入的位置是什么？
Then this is going to read from file descriptor three and into this buffer.
然后这将从文件描述符三读取数据，并存入该缓冲区中。
And you are going to copy the data from position 100 in the file.
你需要从文件中的位置100复制数据。
So from position 100 or five,
所以从位置100或者五开始，
identified by the script or three,
由脚本或三个标识符识别。
read data into this buffer.
将数据读入该缓冲区。
But really is the way you need to think about this,
但实际上，这是你需要思考的方式，
that instead of this file,
而不是这个文件，
you are going to have I number,
你将会拥有一个I数字。
like I mentioned from here,
就像我之前在这里提到的一样，
you just leave your point directly to this.
你直接表达你的观点就好。
I number points to an eye note.
我将数字标记为眼睛注释。
But let me ask you this question.
但是让我问你这个问题。
Why do you think instead of food or text?
为什么你认为我会选择食物而不是文字？
Here I should just skip the eye number,
这里我应该跳过眼睛的编号。
right?
对的吗？
Which is how and identified by the operating system of that particular file.
这是由操作系统识别和标识特定文件的方式。
Why?
为了帮助更多的学生理解和学习操作系统课程，我作为助教会将英文内容翻译成中文。这样可以让更多的学生受益，并提供更好的学习体验。
I know, but now not full text.
我知道，但现在没有完整的文本。
Let me help you a little bit.
让我帮你一点忙。
Look at this picture while I numbers and not
看着这张图片，我看到的是数字而不是
file up text.
请上传文本文件。
I don't want to name my fallacy random numbers.
我不想给我的谬误随机取名字。
It's again, you don't name.
这是再次发来的消息，你没有署名。
It's let me very, very clear here.
这让我非常非常清楚。
From the operating system,
从操作系统角度来看，
from your application perspective,
从您的应用程序角度来看，
you open a file.
你打开了一个文件。
When you open a file,
当你打开一个文件时，
you open food or texts.
你可以打开食物或者文字。
And back, you don't get a file descriptor.
而且，你不会得到一个文件描述符。
So the file descriptors points to a data structure,
因此，文件描述符指向一个数据结构，
which is open file description.
打开文件描述符（Open File Description）是一个在操作系统中用于标识和访问打开文件的整数值。每当应用程序打开一个文件时，操作系统会为该文件分配一个唯一的文件描述符。通过使用文件描述符，应用程序可以对文件进行读取、写入和其他操作。文件描述符是操作系统中文件管理的重要概念之一。
This is in the kernel.
这是在内核中。
You see everything which is below this dotted line.
你可以看到这条虚线以下的所有内容。
It's in the kernel here.
这是在内核中。
And I show you this example.
我给你展示这个例子。
I will show you that this file is a food or text, right?
我会向您展示这个文件是食物还是文本，对吗？
Because this is what you opened.
因为这是你打开的。
But what we are saying here is that we really don't want to keep
但我们在这里说的是，我们真的不想保留
in the open file descriptor,
在打开的文件描述符中，
food or text.
食物或文本。
Instead, I want to keep the eye number of the food or text.
相反，我想保留食物或文本的眼睛数量。
The question, why do I want to keep I number here in this data structure?
为什么我想要在这个数据结构中保留一个I数字？
Instead of food or text?
而不是食物或文字？
File dot text is directory,
文件 dot text 是一个目录。
the directory independent.
独立的目录
That's a very good point.
这是一个非常好的观点。
Let's say.
假设吧。
It's not for dot text.
这不是用于点文本的。
Is the entire pathway.
整个路径。
Yes,
是的，
the jasper is correct.
Jasper 是正确的。
Save that the first translation step, it's exact.
保存第一步的翻译，它是准确的。
You see,
你看到，
I open the file and I get the file descriptor.
我打开文件并获得了文件描述符。
So then I want,
那么我想要，
if I keep the I number instead of file pass,
如果我保留I节点号而不是文件路径的话，
then i'd save this translation step.
那么我会保存这个翻译步骤。
Otherwise, whenever I am going to access a file,
否则，每当我要访问一个文件时，
I need to do this translation because I have filed a text.
我需要进行这个翻译，因为我需要整理一篇文本。
I need to do the translation to get the I number.
我需要进行翻译以获取I号码。
So I save this step.
所以我保存这个步骤。
Very good.
非常好。
Let me just go a little bit quicker.
让我稍微快一点。
You have a fine line in a particular directory,
你在一个特定目录中有一条精细的线。
in a particular directory, you are going,
在一个特定的目录中，你要去的是
the file name is going.
文件名是going。
It's you can think about a it's a bunch of entries in these directories.
你可以将其想象成这些目录中的一系列条目。
The file name offset is by going to tell you,
文件名偏移量是通过查看来告诉你的。
the offset is going to tell you and what is the particle?
偏移量会告诉你什么，粒子是什么？
What is the entry for my particular file?
我的特定文件的入口是什么？
Then for file numbers,
那么对于文件编号，
you are going to have file number offset.
你需要有文件号和偏移量。
Basically, this is what it's I number.
基本上，这就是 I 节点的含义。
The eye number is.
眼睛的编号是。
You have an index structure,
你有一个索引结构，
which is indexed by itself.
这个索引是以它自己为索引的。
I node, each entering this index structure.
I节点，每个进入该索引结构。
It's an I node which represents all the information associated with that file.
这是一个表示与该文件相关的所有信息的I节点。
The index in that index structure is the I number.
该索引结构中的索引是I号。
Right?
对吗？
You have.
你有。
And the open operation performed his name resolution,
并且打开操作执行了名称解析。
basically translating the file name into the file number.
将文件名基本上翻译为文件编号。
And the read and write operations are only referring to the file number.
读取和写入操作仅涉及文件编号。
So you avoid the first translation step.
所以你可以跳过第一步的翻译。
You use a file number as an index to locate the I node.
你使用文件号作为索引来定位I节点。
And the I node is going to leave you to the blocks.
然后I节点将把你交给块。
We'll see, there are a few examples.
我们会看到的，有一些例子。
You have three come.
你有三个选择。
Four components is a directory.
四个组件构成一个目录。
The index structure is a storage blocks and free space map.
索引结构是存储块和空闲空间映射。
Remember about that?
还记得那件事吗？
How do you get the file number?
你如何获取文件编号？
You have to look in the directory structure in the directory structure.
你需要在目录结构中查找目录结构。
I told you that in directory structure,
我告诉过你，在目录结构中，
you have entries associated with each file.
每个文件都有关联的条目。
Each entry I didn't tell you what each entry contains,
每个条目我没有告诉你每个条目包含什么内容，
but each entry i'm telling you,
但是每个条目我都告诉你，
now each entry a it's a topple,
现在每个条目都是一个元组，
which contain its maps a file name to the file number.
其中包含将文件名映射到文件号的映射。
Again, when i'm talking about file number,
再次，当我谈论文件编号时，
I am also final file number is the same like I number.
我的最终文件编号也和我的学号一样。
This file number can be a file or another directory.
这个文件号可以是一个文件或者另一个目录。
The operation system starts a mapping in the directory and interpret this format.
操作系统在目录中启动一个映射，并解释这个格式。
This double or the mapping between file name and file number is
这个双重映射是文件名和文件编号之间的映射。
for directory entry.
对于目录项。
It's very important to feel to understand like again that the way we
再次感受到理解的重要性，我们的方式
manipulate the directory,
操作目录，
although in unix, a directory,
尽管在Unix中，一个目录，
just another five,
再来五个。
is different despite the fact that at the lower level is directory,
尽管在较低层级上是目录，但它仍然是不同的。
just another files,
只是另一个文件。
the way you manipulate the directory is different than the way you
处理目录的方式与你处理的方式不同
manipulated a file.
操作了一个文件。
Right?
对吗？
You cannot just use the read operation on the file.
你不能仅仅使用读取操作来操作文件。
You need to have special operations.
你需要进行特殊操作。
Redirectory create directory,
Redirectory 创建目录,
or make directory and so forth.
或者创建目录等等。
But let me ask you this question.
但是让我问你这个问题。
I why don't I again,
为什么我不再试一次呢？
since at the lower level,
由于在较低层次上，
the directory is just another file.
目录只是另一个文件。
Why don't I allow the application to do read and write some directors?
为什么我不允许应用程序读写某些目录？
It's dangerous,
这很危险。
right?
对的？
You can override if you override these mappings,
如果你覆盖了这些映射关系，你就可以进行覆盖操作。
you messings up,
你搞砸了。
because these mapping are maintained by the operating system.
因为这些映射是由操作系统维护的。
Right?
对吗？
It's for the same reason.
这是同样的原因。
You don't allow your process to arbitrarily modify kernel data structures
你不允许进程随意修改内核数据结构。
that this is how the directory looks like.
这是目录的样子。
Everyone knows that.
每个人都知道。
So directories are typically organized as trees,
因此，目录通常被组织成树形结构，
directory trees.
目录树
The leaves in the trees are files.
树上的叶子是文件。
The interior now is in the trees,
现在室内是在树林中。
including the root are directories.
包括根目录在内，都是目录。
Like I said,
就像我说的一样，
you do not allow the application to manipulate,
你不允许应用程序进行操作。
to read and write directly on the directories.
直接读写目录。
Instead to manipulate directories,
而不是操作目录，
you have special function called system calls,
你有一个特殊的功能叫做系统调用。
right?
对的？
Make beer or remove beer,
酿造啤酒或清除啤酒,
create a directory.
创建一个目录。
Already dear to traverse the directory structure.
已经亲爱地遍历了目录结构。
This is from the command line.
这是来自命令行。
You can use from the command line.
你可以从命令行中使用。
But you also can use them.
但是你也可以使用它们。
You have lipstick support.
你有口红支持。
You can have also use a library.
你也可以使用一个库。
So you can use this programmatic from your application link and unlink.
所以你可以从你的应用程序中使用这个编程接口来链接和取消链接。
This allows you to actually break actually this hierarchy.
这实际上允许您打破这种层次结构。
Actually, you can have a name of a file.
实际上，你可以给一个文件取一个名字。
You can have a file,
你可以拥有一个文件。
a name pointing to an existing file.
一个指向已存在文件的名称。
Right?
对吗？
So you have a file with a namesake food or text.
所以你有一个与食物或文本同名的文件。
Now I can have another name called full one dot s pointing to the same file.
现在我可以给它另一个名字，叫做full.one.s，指向同一个文件。
We'll learn more about that.
我们将会更多地了解这个。
Just to give you a sense.
只是为了让你有个概念。
Now, let's assume that about the overhead which are involved,
现在，让我们假设涉及的开销。
let's assume that we want to access to resolve this,
假设我们想要解决这个问题，
to get the I number of the file count,
获取文件计数的I号码。
right?
对的？
And then to access the file count.
然后访问文件计数。
So what do we need to do here?
那么我们在这里需要做什么？
First of all, we need to locate the root of the director.
首先，我们需要定位目录的根目录。
We need to start searching from somewhere from the root of the directory.
我们需要从目录的根目录开始搜索。
And the root for how do we do that?
那么我们如何做到呢？
Fortunately,
幸运的是，
by convention,
按照惯例，
the operating system as the file system,
操作系统作为文件系统，
put the route directory,
将路由目录放在这里。
the route in a fixed position on the disk.
磁盘上的固定位置路径。
You access this block,
你访问了这个块。
data block forward.
数据块转发。
In the data block, the road,
在数据块中，道路，
you have you have this kind of directory entries,
你有这种类型的目录条目，
file entries in that directory.
该目录中的文件条目。
Is that a directory?
这是一个目录吗？
You are going to have to locate mike,
你需要找到迈克。
right?
对的吗？
How you do that?
你是如何做到的？
You can linearly search.
你可以进行线性搜索。
Typically, the number of entries in the directory is small.
通常情况下，目录中的条目数量较少。
Now, once you locate,
现在，一旦你找到位置，
you read the file header for mike,
你读取了Mike的文件头。
because how do you know that?
因为你怎么知道呢？
Because the entry for my tells you what is the file number or four directory,
因为my的条目告诉你文件号或四个目录的内容。
mike.
迈克。
So from that,
从那个角度来看，
you go and it read again the first data block in my you search for the book,
你继续前进并重新读取我在你搜索书籍时的第一个数据块。
the self, my is going to gain.
自我，我的目标是获得成长。
It's a director.
这是一个导演。
It's going to keep a bunch of directory file entries.
它将保存一系列目录文件条目。
You read the header for the book.
你阅读了这本书的封面。
Again, you find book.
再次，你找到了书。
The book entry,
这本书的条目，
the book entry is going to have the file number associated with a book.
图书条目将与图书关联的文件编号。
Directory use that in order to read the header for book.
使用目录来读取书的标题。
And then you read the first data block for a book,
然后你读取了一本书的第一个数据块。
you search for account,
你要搜索账户。
you find count,
你需要找到计数。
and the count is you get the file number for count.
并且计数是你获得计数的文件编号。
There is a file header for account.
账户有一个文件头。
And now you are done.
现在你已经完成了。
So how many axis is?
这个问题不太清楚，请提供更多的背景信息。你是在问什么轴？是指坐标轴吗？
1234567,
一百二十三万四千五百六十七
just to do this resolution.
只是为了完成这个决议。
Now you see how important is to keep in the description of the file to keep I
现在你明白了在文件描述中保持一致性的重要性。
number for the file number instead of just the file name.
将文件名替换为文件编号。
Because I save the next time after I open it.
因为我在打开后保存了下一次的时间。
The next time when I do a read and write,
下次当我进行读写操作时，
I save seven axis and that expensive.
我保存了七个轴，而且很贵。
You also have the notion of current directories and the current directories.
你还有当前目录和当前目录的概念。
It's if you just refer to the file name without ignoring the past name,
如果你只是引用文件名而不忽略之前的名称，那么就是这样。
you are referring that you assume that in the current director,
你是在指你假设在当前目录下。
the current directory,
当前目录
it's already cached.
已经缓存了。
So it's one way with to reduce this number of counts.
所以有一种方法可以减少这个计数的数量。
This is how happened the file structure in the memory.
这是文件在内存中的结构发生的方式。
And this is a user space,
这是一个用户空间，
a kernel memory,
内核内存
and it's a secondary story.
这是一个次要的故事。
This is what happened on the disk.
这是磁盘上发生的情况。
You have read when you read a file descriptor,
当你读取一个文件描述符时，你已经读取了
this a file descriptor paying points into this per process open file paper.
这是一个文件描述符，用于将点数支付到每个进程打开的文件纸上。
This each of this entry,
这是每个条目中的每个部分。
it's information associated with that file.
这是与该文件相关的信息。
And what you are going to get here is a file number and the sick position
在这里，您将获得一个文件号和病人的位置信息。
of the current position in the file.
当前位置在文件中的偏移量。
You see this grazing here.
你看到这里的放牧吗？
It's again, recently.
最近又是这样。
Let me show you just to connect the dots.
让我给你展示一下如何连接这些点。
Oops.
哎呀。
Is this one?
这个是吗？
The information in that gray area?
那个灰色区域中的信息是什么？
Is this open file description?
这是一个打开的文件描述符吗？
Right?
对吗？
The I number and the position is a file.
I节点号和位置是一个文件。
This is what is here.
这是这里的内容。
The I number points you to the I node.
I号码指向I节点。
This is the open file tables,
这是打开文件表。
and the I node has protection bids.
I节点具有保护位。
And then also has all these maintains all these data blocks.
然后还需要维护所有这些数据块。
And all this is maintained,
而所有这些都是被维护的，
is maintained also on the disk.
也在磁盘上维护。
I know the Information is maintained on the disk,
我知道信息是存储在磁盘上的。
because it maintains the association between that file number and the blocks,
因为它维护了文件编号与块之间的关联关系，
data blocks where the data of the file is located.
数据块是存储文件数据的地方。
It must be on the disk.
它必须在磁盘上。
It must be durable because it must persist.
它必须耐用，因为它必须持久存在。
After you've finish your program after the program ends.
在程序结束后，你可以完成你的程序。
We talk about all of these things.
我们谈论所有这些事情。
I'm going to end up with this a few interesting data.
我最终会得到一些有趣的数据。
And then we are going to continue next time with the file system.
然后我们下次将继续讲解文件系统。
So this is a study.
这是一项研究。
It was 13,
是13点。
14 years ago,
14年前，
but it still is very relevant.
但它仍然非常相关。
And this is the point here is the following.
这里的重点是接下来的内容。
So what this study is looking over 5 years and is looking
这项研究将持续5年，并进行观察。
about how the distribution of the file lengths.
关于文件长度的分布情况。
And that's the Information about statistics about the files in a file system.
这是关于文件系统中文件统计信息的信息。
The first important one is basically show you what is the size of the file,
第一个重要的是基本上展示了文件的大小。
the distribution of the file sizes for a file system.
文件系统中文件大小的分布。
Basically, what this tells you,
基本上，这告诉你的是，
this is on the x axis of file sites and the number of files on the y axis.
这是文件站点的 x 轴和文件数量的 y 轴。
This is for different girls,
这是给不同的女孩们的。
is for different years.
是针对不同年份的。
So you have something similar,
所以你有类似的东西，
although as a years pass,
尽管随着时间的推移，
you have more and more files.
你有越来越多的文件。
Right?
对吗？
The main point here is,
这里的主要观点是，
this is showing that most of the files are small,
这显示大部分文件都很小，
not is that the x axis is log scale.
不是x轴是对数刻度。
These are very small, right?
这些很小，对吗？
For instance, most of the files are 512 kilobytes or less.
例如，大多数文件的大小为512千字节或更小。
There are very few large files.
有非常少的大文件。
So most of the files are small files.
大部分文件都是小文件。
However, if you look,
然而，如果你仔细观察，
but if I'm taking some piece of data,
但是如果我正在获取一些数据，
and I'm asking the question from the files,
我从文件中提出这个问题。
from all the file system, I'm taking a piece of data.
从所有的文件系统中，我正在提取一段数据。
And I'm asking the question,
而我正在提出问题，
what is the size of the file which contains this piece of data?
包含这段数据的文件大小是多少？
Then this is the answer I'm going to get.
那么这就是我将要得到的答案。
And basically, you see now that most of the data is contains in big files.
基本上，你现在可以看到大部分的数据都包含在大文件中。
The majority of files is small,
大部分文件都很小，
but the man,
但是那个人，
the big files are responsible for most of the data.
大文件负责大部分数据。
Okay?
好的？
I am going to end up with a question to you.
我将要向你提出一个问题。
It's a fun question.
这是一个有趣的问题。
You see,
你看，
you see here that on this kind of this distribution,
你可以看到，在这种分布上，
you have two picks.
你有两个选择。
You have AA pick around 2 megabytes and another peak around one gigabyte.
你有一个大约2兆字节的峰值和另一个大约1千兆字节的峰值。
You have why do you think you have these topics?
你为什么认为你有这些话题？
Why do you think what this one gigabyte?
你为什么认为这是一个千兆字节？
What do you think causes?
你认为是什么原因导致的？
And by the way, in 2000,
顺便说一下，2000年的时候，
it wasn't such a big,
这不是一个很大的问题，
but as a time goes, went on, passes passed,
但随着时间的流逝，过去了，过去的时光已经过去了。
you have this big?
你有这个大吗？
Let's see.
让我们看看。
Yes, that sounds very good to answer here, right?
是的，这听起来很好，我可以在这里回答问题吗？
We know, right?
我们知道，对吧？
It's like,
就像是，
especially that was peer to peer system and you write about it.
尤其是那个点对点系统，你写了关于它的内容。
Yes, this is one reason is media.
是的，这是一个原因，即媒体。
The other reason this is a lot bigger and bigger files are also binary files.
另一个原因是文件越来越大，而且这些文件也是二进制文件。
The executive become bigger over time.
随着时间的推移，执行文件变得越来越大。
That's excellent answers.
这是非常出色的答案。
With this, we are going to stop here.
到此为止，我们要停下来了。
Again, good luck to the middle of tomorrow,
再次祝你明天中间好运，
and i'll see you again on Saturday.
我会在周六再见到你。
Thank you.
谢谢你。